翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
As the last video of the day, let's consider adding a method called get that is going to return the i-th item from the list.
作为今天的最后一个视频，让我们考虑添加一个名为 get 的方法
该方法返回 List 中的第 i 个项目
We're going to say the front item is the zeroth item.
我们称最前面的是第0项
And for simplicity, to keep your code simple,
简单起见
it's OK to assume that whatever someone asks for actually exists.
假设请求的东西是存在的
So in other words, if they ask for item a million and the list only has five things, that's fine.
如果请求一百万个项，而 List 中只有五项也可以
It's OK if your code crashes.
代码崩溃了也没有关系
So as an example, let's suppose this is our list right here.
假设这是我们的 List
If we ask for l.get 0, we should get back five.
请求 l.get(0)，应该得到5
Or if we ask for l.get 1, we should get back 10.
或者请求 l.get(1)，应该得到10
So what I'd like you to do is really sit down and think about this and don't just skip to the answer.
好好考虑一下，不要直接跳到答案处
The best way, I think, to work on this is on paper.
最好在纸上画画
Though, if you want, you can also do it by looking in the lectureCode repo
也可以查看课程代码来实现
and grabbing the file called intList.java in the lists1/exercises folder.
找到 lists1/exercises 文件夹中名为 intList.java 的文件
And if you really insist, you can do it in your head,
也可以在脑子中做
but that's no fun.
但那并不好玩
So give it a shot.
试一试吧
You can use recursion or iteration,
你可以使用递归或迭代
but spoiler, I'm going to use recursion in my solution.
剧透一下，我要使用递归
So pause the video, and then I'll tell you what I did.
暂停视频，一会揭晓
OK, so let's do it.
好的，我们开始吧
We need a get method.
我们需要 get 方法
So I'm going to call public int get int i,
public int get(int i)
and it's going to return the i-th item of this list.
它返回该 List 的第 i 项
I'll even say it's an IntList.
或者说是 IntList
So I want to do it recursively, which means I need a base case.
我想使用递归，这就需要边界条件
What should the base case be?
边界条件是什么？
Now, even if you haven't figured it out,
即使你还没有弄清楚
maybe think about that question.
也可以考虑一下这个问题
So it turns out that the most natural base case has nothing to do with the tail or the rest, I mean, or the first.
边界条件与尾项或 rest 无关，应该是 first 项
Instead, it's if someone asks me or for my zeroth item,
如果请求获取第0项
I should just return what?
应该返回什么？
Well, I should just return the first item.
返回 first 项
I just give the data.
我只提供数据
That's what's at the front of the list.
这就是 List 前面的内容
You asked me for zero.
你请求0
I return first.
我返回 first
Now, if someone has a larger i, an i of, say, one or two or three, then I don't have the value.
如果请求更大的 i，比方说 1 2 3，那么我就没有价值了
Someone else does.
应该交给其他人去做
And it's important to keep in mind that what's my value one is my neighbor,
重要的是，我最看重我的邻居
or my rest, value zero.
或者称为我的 rest
Or what's my fifth value is my neighbors fourth, neighbors third, neighbors second, neighbors first,
第五个值是我的第4个邻居、第3个邻居、第2个邻居、第1个邻居
neighbors zero, all the way down the line, if that makes sense.
第0个邻居，顺着这个思路
So in other words, I need to ask the rest of the list for something.
换句话说，我需要向 List 的 rest 请求
Rest.size-- sorry, not right.
rest.size()，抱歉
I need to ask rest for something.
我要向 rest 请求
What should I ask for?
请求什么呢？
Well, I should ask not for their i-th item,
我不应该要它的第 i 项
but their i minus 1-th item.
而是 i - 1 项
Now, if we try running this, we can just test it out real quick.
现在可以很快运行测试
Let's say we try running it with zero.
假设用0运行
I should get back five.
我应该得到5
Indeed, I do.
的确
How about 2?
2怎么样？
I get back 15.
得到15
1, I get back 10.
1，得到10
And 100, I get some crash.
100，程序崩溃
So it looks like it worked fine.
看起来运行得很好
So if that didn't make total sense, what I encourage you to do is put this through the Java visualizer.
可能没有意义，但我鼓励你将其放到 Java visualizer 中
I'm not going to do it here, because it's actually quite similar to size,
我不打算在这里讲了，因为它实际上和 size() 很相似
and I think it's probably a good exercise for you to jump in and try it out.
这对你来说可能是个很好的练习
But if you've got it, great.
最好做一下
And if you did it iteratively, also great.
反复做也可以
So that's it as far as what I'm going to develop in class.
这就是我要在课堂上讲的东西
So at this point, you probably have the feeling that,
此刻你可能会有这样的感觉
well, while at the beginning we were just kind of lackadaisically thinking about our lives and walruses and whatever else,
一开始我们只是懒散地思考我们的生活、海象之类的东西
at some point, we took off like a rocket and developed this list thing at light speed.
我们迅速升空，光速开发了这个 List
And maybe, just maybe, it feels a little shaky.
也许感觉有点恍惚
So what I'm going to encourage you to do is maybe try a couple more exercises.
所以要多做几个练习
So if you like, there's these extra ungraded exercises called extra IntList practice,
这里有一些不评分的练习
I'll even say dot Java, in the lists1/exercises folder in the lectureCode GitHub directory.
在课程 GitHub 目录的 lists1/Exercises 文件夹中
So if you go to this repository and you open this file,
如果你去这个仓库打开这个文件
you'll see there are two methods waiting to be filled in by you.
将看到有两个方法等待填写
incriList, what it does is it takes a list,
incriList，它接受一个 List
and it increments all the values by the x value here.
将所有的值加 x
And as a constraint, whenever it's done,
还有着一定约束
nothing in the list that you originally created should change.
原来创建的 List 不应更改
Instead, there should be a totally new list
而是创建一个全新的 List
returned by this method, where it has its own copies of everything.
此方法返回所有内容的副本
Down here, you'll write another version of this method called dincrList.
这里你将编写该方法的另一个版本，称为 dincrList
This one, you should not use the keyword new,
这次不应该使用关键字 new
and instead, you should do all the work in place.
再完成所有的工作
So once you jump into this, you'll see it's a little challenging to think about what exactly--
这里你会发现有一些挑战性
how you're going to approach this and what these two things mean.
如何处理它们，以及这两个任务的意义
So give it a shot.
去试一试吧
And feel free to post on Piazza or talk to your friends
你可以在 Piazza 上发布帖子或与朋友讨论
and work this out-- it's not for a grade--
解决这个问题，不为了分数
and try and figure out a solution.
试着想出一个解决方案
So that's it for today.
今天就到这里吧
So even though, right now, it may seem a little intimidating that we're flying through lists,
现在我们在 List 中穿梭，可能有点吓人
we're going to spend a lot of time on these
需要花很多时间在这上面
and get really fluent with them and become super magical list creator people.
流畅地使用它们，创造更神奇的 List
It wasn't the greatest and most rousing close,
这还不是最激动人心的结尾
but hey, we've got, what, 37 more to go.
还有37课要学
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
So I'll take it.
那就到这吧